JONATHAN MCGECHIE

Forest Grove, OR • 503-679-5308 jjmcgechie@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanmcgechie

Education

Master of Data Science Willamette University

August 2024

Bachelor of Science: Applied Mathematics

August 2017

New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology (New Mexico Tech)

Summary

Proven record of facilitating support services in a fast-paced work environment. Strong organizational and communication skills with the ability to manage multiple business affairs simultaneously. Versatile skill set applicable to any business setting, creating and maintaining high levels of efficiency and productivity. Advanced understanding of data entry and analytics, resulting in superior service. Trusted advocate, department liaison, and data analyst.

Skills

Programming Languages: R, Python (Pandas, Numpy)

Database: PostgreSQL, Agile, Paycom, Microsoft Dynamics AX, Salesforce-

Lightning, SmartSuite

Certifications: Google Suite, Microsoft Office, Pro/Expert/Consultant SmartSuite Other Skills: Microsoft Office Products (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint),

Microsoft Office Products (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint)

Leadership skills, Google Suite.

Work Experience

Database Administrator BrigaCare April 2024 – July 2024

- Developed and maintained automations within SmartSuite to optimize workflows and increase efficiency.
- Trained new employees on the effective use of SmartSuite, ensuring smooth onboarding and proficient use of platform
- Created custom views and dashboards tailored to meet specific clients needs, enhancing data visibility and accessibility.
- Managed the day-to-day operations of the client database, ensuring data integrity and seamless functionality.

Data Specialist Biamp April 2022 – January 2024

- Assisted in large-scale changes, including product name changes and End-of-Life processing for three product lines.
- Removed over \$1.9 million dollars of obsolete stock in 20 months.
- Led warranty and cost analysis of End-of-Life products
- Maintained accurate record-keeping.
- Developed and enhanced data entry and analytics
- Acted as an interdisciplinary liaison, ensuring effective communication between leadership and departments.
- Managed and oversaw Manufacture Change Order requests.

Production Scheduler/Planner Davis tools December 2021 – March 2022

- Reviewed customer purchase orders for accuracy and MRP system entry.
- Assisted with compliance in state and federal mandates, including internal audits.
- Developed a system for efficient communication of purchase order quotes.
- Analyzed data to facilitate purchase orders and anticipate customer needs.
- Maintained daily contact with multiple departments.
- Completed purchase order cycle with required documentation.
- Prepared reports for senior leadership and clients on shipments and order scheduling.
- Processed purchase requisitions for the purchasing department with outside vendors.

Billing Assistant DAT Solutions June 2020 – July 2021

- Data Processing accounts and reviewing accounts with Salesforce-Lighting.
- Addressed customers' needs and provided account review.
- Posted AP to appropriate accounts
- Worked outstanding accounts to reduce AR and remove bad debt from company books.